NICOLAS MAVRIDES

SOFTWARE ENGINEER # MANCHESTER, UK

+44 7873232548 # Micmavr1@gmail.com # nicolasmavrides.co.uk https://github.com/NicolasMavrides # https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicolas-mavrides-722a62139

Summary

Computer Science graduate from the University of Sheffield with work experience in the industry. As a dedicated Software Engineer, maximum success & quality is something I always strive for. Maintaining an open-minded, upbeat approach to every task is the foundation of my aim, and thus always make sure that every experience counts by reflection and critical self-evaluation.

Experience

Computer Lab Demonstrator – September 2018 to May 2020 The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK

- Delivered support on Java and Ruby programming tasks to 1st and 2nd year Computer Science students in practical labs.
- Demonstrated suitable code practices, debugging via pair-programming, and clarifying students' queries regarding assignments.

Software Engineering Intern – June 2017 to June 2018 **Rolls-Royce Plc, Birmingham, UK**

- Member of the Development Environment Team which was tasked with developing software solutions to various teams within the company. Liaised between concerned teams to ensure software was of an appropriate standard.
- Enhanced the security of engine software builds by creating an application for generating checksum files.
- Streamlined the testing procedure of projects by developing Python scripts for bundling test components into queues.

Education

Master of Computer Science with a Year in Industry – September 2015 to June 2020 The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK

 Completed 5-year degree with a Year in Industry and dissertation project which consisted of an Internet of Things (IoT) solution for measuring air quality and pollution levels. Graduated with a final grade of First Class with Honours.

Secondary School Education – September 2008 to June 2014 The GC School of Careers, Nicosia, Cyprus

- Awarded a final mark of 85% in School Leaving Report
- Completed A-level subjects in Modern Greek, Mathematics, ICT and Physics, achieving grades A,
 B, B and C respectively.

Technical Skills

- Object-oriented programming: Java, Python, Ruby, C/C++, C#
- Web development: Ruby on Rails, Node.js, PHP
- Mobile development:
 Android Studio with Java and Room
- Software testing:
 Unit testing & Test-driven-development
 (TDD) with JUnit, NUnit and RSpec suites
- Database development: SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB
- Linux Operating Systems
- Internet of Things:
 Microcontroller circuits with Arduino C++ programming
- Microsoft Azure DevOps
- European Computer Driving License (ECDL)

Conferences / Activites

- Capco Build Your Own Bank Hackathon | https://www.capco.com/Solutions/Capco-Digital/Build-a-digital-bank-from-scratch | London, UK | September 2019
 Presented a customer loyalty scheme system for a digital bank model proposed by Capco Digital
- International Student Week in Belgrade 2019 | http://www.iswib.org/ | Belgrade, Serbia | July 2019
 Created a 2D "Spaceship invasion" game at game development workshop using Unity and C# programming
- Istanbul Tech Talks 2018 | http://www.istanbultechtalks.com/ | Istanbul, Turkey | April 2018
 Conference on various software development topics, hosted by Istanbul Technical University
- FOSDEM 2018 | https://fosdem.org/ | Brussels, Belgium | February 2018 Open-source developer conference, hosted by Université libre de Bruxelles
- Freenode #live 2017 | https://freenode.live/ | Bristol, UK | November 2017
 Open-source projects conference, organized and hosted on behalf of the Freenode IRC network
- ShefJam4 | http://shefjam.com/ | Sheffield, UK | March 2017
 24-hour Game Jam event, hosted by the University of Sheffield Computer Science Society.
- Engineering You're Hired! 2017 | http://www.yourehired.group.shef.ac.uk/wp/ | Sheffield, UK | January 2017
 - Week-long group project at the Uni. of Sheffield on developing an Augmented Reality headset for extreme sports
- HackSheffield 2016 | https://www.hacksheffield.co/ | Sheffield, UK | October 2016
 24-hour Hackathon, hosted by the University of Sheffield
- Google Hash Code 2016 | https://hashcode.withgoogle.com/ | Sheffield, UK | February 2016
 Participated in a team of fellow students to solve the "Optimization of Drone Deliveries" problem given by Google
- GEC Week 2016 | https://www.sheffield.ac.uk/civil/ug/global-engineering-challenge/ | Sheffield, UK | January 2016
 - Week-long project at the University of Sheffield on tackling electricity shortages in Africa with sustainable methods. Brainstormed and proposed an engineering solution titled "Electrical Supply Infrastructure with Renewable Sources".